[Music]
I am I am a
Visionary Illuminating galaxies
to witness the birth of [Music]
stars and sharpening our understanding of extreme
weather [Music] events I am a helper
guiding the blind through a crowded
world I was thinking about running
to the store and giving voice to
those who cannot speak to not make me laugh I am a
Transformer harnessing gravity to
store Renewable [Music] Power [Music]
and Paving the way towards unlimited clean
energy for us [Music] all I am a
[Music] trainer teaching robots to
assist to watch out for
[Music] danger and help save
lives I am a Healer providing a
new generation of cures and new
levels of patient care doctor that I am
allergic to penicillin is it still okay
to take the medications definitely these
antibiotics don't contain penicillin so
it's perfectly safe for you to take them I
am a navigator [Music] generating virtual
scenarios to let us safely explore the real
world and understand every [Music]
decision I even helped write the
script breathe life into the words [Music]
I am AI brought to life by Nvidia
deep learning and Brilliant Minds
everywhere
please welcome to the stage Nvidia founder and CEO
Jensen [Music] [Applause] [Music] Wong welcome to
GTC I hope you realize this is not a
concert you have arrived at
a developers conference there
will be a lot of science described
algorithms computer architecture
mathematics I sensed a very heavy weight in the
room all of a sudden almost like you were in
the wrong place no no conference in the world
is there a great assembly of researchers from
such diverse fields of science from climatech to
radio Sciences trying to figure out how to use AI
to robotically control MOS for Next Generation 6G
radios robotic self-driving car s even artificial
intelligence even artificial intelligence
everybody's first I noticed a sense of relief
there all of all of a sudden also this conference
is represented by some amazing companies this list
this is not the attendees these are the
presentors and what's amazing is this if
you take away all of my friends close friends
Michael Dell is sitting right there in the IT
industry all of the friends I grew up with in
the industry if you take away that list this is
what's amazing these are the presenters of the
non it Industries using accelerated Computing
to solve problems that normal computers
can't it's represented in life sciences
healthc Care genomics Transportation of
course retail Logistics manufacturing
industrial the gamut of Industries represented
is truly amazing and you're not here to attend
only you're here to present to talk about
your research $100 trillion dollar of the
world's Industries is represented in
this room today this is absolutely
amazing there is absolutely something
happening there is something going on
the industry is being transformed not just ours
because the computer industry the computer is
the single most important instrument of society
today fundamental transformations in Computing
affects every industry but how did we start
how did we get here I made a little cartoon
for you literally I drew this in one page
this is nvidia's Journey started in 1993
this might be the rest of the talk 1993 this
is our journey we were founded in 1993 there
are several important events that happen
along the way I'll just highlight a few
in 2006 Cuda which has turned out to have been
a revolutionary Computing model we thought it
was revolutionary then it was going to be an
overnight success and almost 20 years later it
happened we saw it
coming two decades
later in 2012 alexnet Ai and Cuda made first
Contact in 2016 recognizing the importance
of this Computing model we invented a brand
new type of computer we called the dgx one
170 Tera flops in this supercomputer eight
gpus connected together for the very first
time I hand delivered the very first dgx-1 to
a startup located in San Francisco called open
AI dgx-1 was the world's first AI supercomputer
remember 170 Tera flops 2017 the Transformer
arrived 2022 chat GPT capture the world's
imag imaginations have people realize the
importance and the capabilities of artificial
intelligence and 2023 generative AI emerged and
a new industry begins why why is a new industry
because the software never existed before we are
now producing software using computers to write
software producing software that never existed
before it is a brand new category it took share
from nothing it's a brand new category and the
way you produce the software is unlike anything
we've ever done before in data centers generating
tokens producing floating Point numbers at very
large scale as if in the beginning of this last
Industrial Revolution when people realized
that you would set up factories apply energy
to it and this invisible valuable thing called
electricity came out AC generators and 100 years
later 200 years later we are now creating new
types of electrons tokens using infrastructure
we call factories AI factories to generate this
new incredibly valuable thing called artificial
intelligence a new industry has emerged well
well we're going to talk about many things
about this new industry we're going to talk
about how we're going to do Computing next
we're going to talk about the type of software
that you build because of this new industry the
new software how you would think about this
new software what about applications in this
new industry and then maybe what's next and
how can we start preparing today for what is
about to come next well but before I start I
want to show you the soul of Nvidia the soul
of our company at the intersection of computer
Graphics physics and artificial intelligence
all intersecting inside a computer in Omniverse
in a virtual world simulation everything we're
going to show you today literally everything
we're going to show you today is a simulation
not animation it's only beautiful because it's
physics the world is beautiful it's only amazing
because it's being animated with robotics it's
being animated with artificial intelligence what
you're about to see all day it's completely
generated completely simulated and Omniverse
and all of it what you're about to enjoy is the
world's first concert where everything is homemade
everything is homemade you're about to watch
some home videos so sit back and enjoy [Music]
[Music]
yourself [Music]
m
[Music]
what
0:13:29.120,1193:02:47.295
[Music]
a
God I love it
Nvidia accelerated Computing has reached the
Tipping Point general purpose Computing has
run out of steam we need another way of doing
Computing so that we can continue to scale so
that we can continue to drive down the cost of
computing so that we can continue to consume
more and more Computing while being sustainable
accelerated Computing is a dramatic speed up over
general purpose Computing and in every single
industry we engage and I'll show you many the
impact is dramatic but in no industry is a
more important than our own the industry of
using simulation tools to create products in this
industry it is not about driving down the cost of
computing it's about driving up the scale of
computing we would like to be able to sim at
the entire product that we do completely
in full Fidelity completely digitally in
essentially what we call digital twins we would
like to design it build it simulate it operate it
completely digitally in order to do that we need
to accelerate an entire industry and today I would
like to announce that we have some Partners who
are joining us in this journey to accelerate their
entire ecosystem so that we can bring the world
into accelerated Computing but there's a bonus
when you become accelerated your infrastructure
is cou to gpus and when that happens it's exactly
the same infrastructure for generative Ai and
so I'm just delighted to announce several very
important Partnerships there are some of the most
important companies in the world and Anis does
engineering simulation for what the world makes
we're partnering with them to Cuda accelerate the
Ansys ecosystem to connect Ansys to the Omniverse
digital twin incredible the thing that's really
great is that the install base of media GPU
accelerated systems are all over the world in
every cloud in every system all over Enterprises
and so the app the applications they accelerate
will have a giant installed base to go serve end
users will have amazing applications and of course
system makers and csps will have great customer
demand synopsis synopsis is nvidia's literally
first software partner they were there in very
first day of our company synopsis revolutionized
the chip industry with high level design we
are going to Cuda accelerate synopsis we're
accelerating computational lithography one of
the most important applications that nobody's
ever known about in order to make chips we have
to push lithography to limit Nvidia has created
a library domain specific library that accelerates
computational lithography incredibly once we can
accelerate and software Define all of tsmc who
is announcing today that they're going to go into
production with Nvidia kitho once this software
defined and accelerated the next step is to apply
generative AI to the future of semiconductor
manufacturing push in Geometry even further
Cadence builds the world's essential Eda and SDA
tools we also use Cadence between these three
companies ansis synopsis and Cadence we basically
build Nvidia together we are cud accelerating
Cadence they're also building a supercomputer out
of Nvidia gpus so that their customers could do
fluid Dynamic simulation at a 100 a thousand times
scale basically a wind tunnel in real time Cadence
Millennium a supercomputer with Nvidia gpus inside
a software company building supercomputers I love
seeing that building Cadence co-pilots together
imagine a day when Cadence could synopsis ansis
tool providers would offer you AI co-pilots so
that we have thousands and thousands of co-pilot
assistants helping us design chips Design Systems
and we're also going to connect Cadence digital
twin platform to Omniverse as you could see the
trend here we're accelerating the world's CAE Eda
and SDA so that we could create our future in
digital Twins and we're going to connect them
all to Omniverse the fundamental operating
system for future digital twins one of the
industries that benefited tremendously from scale
and you know you all know this one very well large
language model basically after the Transformer
was invented we were able to scale large language
models at incredible rates effectively doubling
every six months now how is it possible that by
doubling every six months that we have grown
the industry we have grown the computational
requirements so far and the reason for that
is quite simply this if you double the size
of the model you double the size of your brain you
need twice as much information to go fill it and
so every time you double your parameter count you
also have to appropriately increase your training
token count the combination of those two numbers
becomes the computation scale you have to support
the latest the state-of-the-art open AI model is
approximately 1.8 trillion parameters 1.8 trillion
parameters required several trillion tokens to go
train so so a few trillion parameters on the order
of a few trillion tokens on the order of when you
multiply the two of them together approximately
30 40 50 billion quadrillion floating Point
operations per second now we just have to do some
Co math right now just hang hang with me so you
have 30 billion quadrillion a quadrillion is like
a paa and so if you had a PA flop GPU you would
need 30 billion seconds to go compute to go train
that model 30 billion seconds is approximately
1,000 years well 1,000 years it's worth
it like to do it sooner but it's worth
it which is usually my answer
when most people tell me hey
how long how long's it going to take to
do something 20 years how it it's worth
it but can we do it next
week and so 1,000 years 1,000 years so what
we need what we need are bigger gpus we need
much much bigger gpus we recognized this early on
and we realized that the answer is to put a whole
bunch of gpus together and of course innovate
a whole bunch of things along the way like
inventing 10 censor cores advancing MV links so
that we could create essentially virtually Giant
gpus and connecting them all together with amazing
networks from a company called melanox infiniband
so that we could create these giant systems and so
djx1 was our first version but it wasn't the last
we built we built supercomputers all the way all
along the way in 2021 we had Seline 4500 gpus or
so and then in 2023 we built one of the largest AI
supercomputers in the world it's just come online
EOS and as we're building these things we're
trying to help the world build these things and in
order to help the world build these things we got
to build them first we build the chips the systems
the networking all of the software necessary
to do this you should see these systems imagine
writing a piece of software that runs across the
entire system Distributing the computation across
thousands of gpus but inside are thousands of
smaller gpus millions of gpus to distribute work
across all of that and to balance the workload so
that you can get the most Energy Efficiency the
best computation time keep your cost down and so
those those fundamental Innovations is what got us
here and here we are as we see the miracle of chat
GPT emerg in front of us we also realize we have a
long ways to go we need even larger models we're
going to train it with multimodality data not
just text on the internet but we're going to we're
going to train it on texts and images and graphs
and charts and just as we learn watching TV and
so there's going to be a whole bunch of watching
video so that these Mo models can be grounded in
physics understands that an arm doesn't go through
a wall and so these models would have common
sense by watching a lot of the world's video
combined with a lot of the world's languages it'll
use things like synthetic data generation just as
you and I do when we try to learn we might use
our imagination to simulate how it's going to
end up just as I did when I Was preparing for
this keynote I was simulating it all along the
way I hope it's going to turn
out as well as I had it in my
head as I was simulating how this keynote was
going to turn out somebody did say that another
performer did her performance completely on
a treadmill so that she could be in shape to
deliver it with full energy I I didn't do that if
I get a l wind at about 10 minutes into this you
know what happened and so so where were we we're
sitting here using synthetic data generation we're
going to use reinforcement learning we're going
to practice it in our mind we're going to have ai
working with AI training each other just like
student teacher Debaters all of that is going
to increase the size of our model it's going
to increase the amount of the amount of data
that we have and we're going to have to build
even bigger gpus Hopper is fantastic but we
need bigger gpus and so ladies and gentlemen I
would like to introduce you to a very very big
[Applause]
GPU named after David Blackwell math
ician game theorists probability we
thought it was a perfect per per perfect
name black wealth ladies and gentlemen enjoy
this
the
com
[Applause] Blackwell is not a chip Blackwell
is the name of a platform uh people think we
make gpus and and we do but gpus don't look
the way they used to here here's the here's
the here's the the if you will the heart
of the blackw system and this inside the
company is not called Blackwell it's
just the number and um uh this this
is Blackwell sitting next to oh this is the
most advanced GPU in the world in production
today this is Hopper this is Hopper
Hopper changed the world this is
Blackwell it's okay
Hopper you're you're very good good good boy
well good girl 208 billion transistors and so
so you could see you I can see that there's a
small line between two dyes this is the first
time two dieses have abutted like this together
in such a way that the two chip the two dieses
think it's one chip there's 10 terabytes of
data between it 10 terabytes per second so
that these two these two sides of the Blackwell
Chip have no clue which side they're on there's
no memory locality issues no cach issues it's
just one giant chip and so uh when we were
told that Blackwell's Ambitions were beyond
the limits of physics uh the engineer said
so what and so this is what what happened and
so this is the Blackwell chip and it goes into
two types of systems the first one is form fit
function compatible to Hopper and so you slide
all Hopper and you push in Blackwell that's the
reason why one of the challenges of ramping is
going to be so efficient there are installations
of Hoppers all over the world and they could be
they could be you know the same infrastructure
same design the power the electricity The
Thermals the software identical push it right
back and so this is a hopper version for the
current hgx configuration and this is what
the other the second Hopper looks like this
now this is a prototype board and um Janine
could I just borrow ladies and gentlemen Jan
Paul and so this this is the this is
a fully functioning board and I just
be careful here this right here is I don't know10
billion the second one's
five it gets cheaper after that so
any customers in the audience it's
okay all right but this is this one's quite
expensive this is to bring up board and um
and the the way it's going to go to production
is like this one here okay and so you're going
to take take this it has two blackw Dy two two
blackw chips and four Blackwell dies connected
to a Grace CPU the grace CPU has a super
fast chipto chip link what's amazing is this
computer is the first of its kind where this much
computation first of all fits into this small of
a place second it's memory coherent they feel
like they're just one big happy family working
on one application together and so everything
is coherent within it um the just the amount
of you know you saw the numbers there's a lot
of terabytes this and terabytes that's um but
this is this is a miracle this is a this let's see
what are some of the things on here uh there's um
uh MV link on top PCI Express on the bottom on
on uh your which one is mine and your left one
of them it doesn't matter uh one of them one
of them is a CPU chipto chip link is my left
or your depending on which side I was just I was
trying to sort that out and I just kind of doesn't
matter hopefully it comes plugged in
so okay so this is the grace Blackwell
system
but there's
more so it turns out it turns out all of the
specs is fantastic but we need a whole lot of
new features uh in order to push the limits
Beyond if you will the limits of physics we
would like to always get a lot more X factors and
so one of the things that we did was We Invented
another Transformer engine another Transformer
engine the second generation it has the ability
to dynamically and automatically rescale and
recas numerical formats to a lower Precision
whenever it can remember artificial intelligence
is about probability and so you kind of have you
know 1.7 approximately 1.7 time approximately
1.4 to be approximately something else does
that make sense and so so the the ability for
the mathematics to retain the Precision and the
range necessary in that particular stage of the
pipeline super important and so this is it's not
just about the fact that we designed a smaller ALU
it's not quite the world's not quite that simple
you've got to figure out when you can use that
across a computation that is thousands of gpus
it's running for weeks and weeks on weeks and you
want to make sure that the the uh uh the training
job is going going to converge and so this new
Transformer engine we have a fifth generation MV
link it's now twice as fast as Hopper but very
importantly it has computation in the network
and the reason for that is because when you
have so many different gpus working together
we have to share our information with each other
we have to synchronize and update each other and
every so often we have to reduce the partial
products and then rebroadcast out the partial
products the sum of the partial products back to
everybody else and so there's a lot of what is
called all reduce and all to all and all gather
it's all part of this area of synchronization
and collectives so that we can have gpus working
with each other having extraordinarily fast links
and being able to do mathematics right in the
network allows us to essentially amplify even
further so even though it's 1.8 terabytes per
second it's effectively higher than that and
so it's many times that of Hopper the likel
Ood of a supercomputer running for weeks on
in is approximately zero and the reason for that
is because there's so many components working at
the same time the statistic the probability of
them working continuously is very low and so
we need to make sure that whenever there is a
well we checkpoint and restart as often as we
can but if we have the ability to detect a weak
chip or a weak note early we could retire it and
maybe swap in another processor that ability
to keep the utilization of the supercomputer
High especially when you just spent $2 billion
building it is super important and so we put in a
Ras engine a reliability engine that does 100%
self test in system test of every single gate
every single bit of memory on the Blackwell
chip and all the memory that's connected to
it it's almost as if we shipped with every
single chip its own Advanced tester that we
CH test our chips with this is the first time
we're doing this super excited about it secure
AI only this conference do they clap for Ras the
the uh secure AI uh obviously you've just spent
hundreds of millions of dollars creating a very
important Ai and the the code the intelligence
of that AI is encoded in the parameters you
want to make sure that on the one hand you
don't lose it on the other hand it doesn't get
contaminated and so we now have the ability to
encrypt data of course at rest but also in transit
and while it's being computed it's all encrypted
and so we now have the ability to encrypt and
transmission and when we're Computing it it is
in a trusted trusted environment trusted
uh engine environment and the last thing
is decompression moving data in and out of these
nodes when the compute is so fast becomes really
essential and so we've put in a high linee speed
compression engine and effectively moves data 20
times times faster in and out of these computers
these computers are are so powerful and there's
such a large investment the last thing we want
to do is have them be idle and so all of these
capabilities are intended to keep Blackwell
fed and as busy as possible overall compared
to Hopper it is two and a half times two and
a half times the fp8 performance for training
per chip it is ALS it also has this new format
called fp6 so that even though the computation
speed is the same the bandwidth that's Amplified
because of the memory the amount of parameters
you can store in the memory is now Amplified
fp4 effectively doubles the throughput this
is vitally important for inference one of the
things that that um is becoming very clear is
that whenever you use a computer with AI on the
other side when you're chatting with the chatbot
when you're asking it to uh review or make an
image remember in the back is a GPU generating
tokens some people call it inference but it's more
appropriately generation the way that Computing
is done in the past was retrieval you would
grab your phone you would touch something um
some signals go off basically an email goes off
to some storage somewhere there's pre-recorded
content somebody wrote a story or somebody made
an image or somebody recorded a video that record
pre-recorded content is then streamed back to
the phone and recomposed in a way based on a
recommender system to present the information to
you you know that in the future the vast majority
of that content will not be retrieved and the
reason for that is because that was pre-recorded
by somebody who doesn't understand the context
which is the reason why we have to retrieve so
much content if you can be working with an AI
that understands the context who you are for
what reason you're fetching this information and
produces the information for you just the way you
like it the amount of energy we save the amount of
networking bandwidth we save the amount of waste
of time we save will be tremendous the future
is generative which is the reason why we call
it generative AI which is the reason why this
is a brand new industry the way we compute is
fundamentally different we created a processor
for the generative AI era and one of the most
important parts of it is content token generation
we call it this format is fp4 well that's a lot
of computation 5x the Gen token generation 5x
the inference capability of Hopper seems like
enough but why stop there the answer is it's
not enough and I'm going to show you why I'm
going to show you why and so we would like to
have a bigger GPU even bigger than this one and
so we decided to scale it and notice but first
let me just tell you how we've scaled over the
course of the last eight years we've increased
computation by 1,000 times8 years 1,000 times
remember back in the good old days of Moore's Law
it was 2x well 5x every what 10 10x every 5 years
that's easier easiest math 10x every 5 years
a 100 times every 10 years 100 times every 10
years at the in the middle in the hey days of the
PC Revolution one 100 times every 10 years in the
last 8 years we've gone 1,000 times we have
two more years to go and so that puts it in
perspective the rate at which we're advancing
Computing is insane and it's still not fast
enough so we built another chip this chip
is just an incredible chip we call it the
Envy link switch it's 50 billion transistors
it's almost the size of Hopper all by itself
this switch ship has four MV links in it
each 1.8 terabytes per second and and it
has computation in as I mentioned what is
this chip for if we were to build such a
chip we can have every single GPU talk to every
other GPU at full speed at the same time that's
insane it doesn't even make sense but if you could
do that if you can find a way to do that and build
a system to do that that's cost effective that's
cost effective how incredible would it be that we
could have all these gpus connect over a coherent
link so that they effectively are one giant GPU
well one of one of the Great Inventions in
order to make a cost effective is that this
chip has to drive copper directly the seres of
this chip is is just a phenomenal invention so
that we could do direct drive to copper and as
a result you can build a system that looks like
this
now this system this system is kind of
insane this is one dgx this is what a dgx
looks like now remember just six years ago
it was pretty heavy but I was able to lift
it I delivered the uh the uh first djx1 to
open Ai and and the researchers there it's
on you know the pictures are on the internet
and uh uh and we all autographed it uh and
um uh if you come to my office it's autographed
there is really beautiful and but but you could
lift it uh this dgx this dgx that djx by
the way was 170 teraflops if you're not
familiar with the numbering system that's
0.17 pedop flops so this is 720 the first
one I delivered to open AI was 0.17 you
could round it up to 0.2 won't make any
difference but and back then was like wow you
know 30 more teraflops and so this is now 720
pedop flops almost an exal flop for training and
the world's first one exal flops machine in one
rack just so you know there are only a
couple two three exop flops machines on
the planet as we speak and so this
is an exop flops AI system in one
single rack well let's take a look at the back of
it so this is what makes it possible
that's the back that's the that's
the back the dgx MV link spine 130
terabytes per second goes through
the back of that chassis that is more
than the aggregate bandwidth of the
internet so we we could basically send everything
to everybody within a second and so so we we have
5,000 cables 5,000 mvlink cables in total 2 miles
now this is the amazing thing if we had to use
Optics we would have had to use transceivers
and retim and those transceivers and reers
alone would have cost 20,000 watts 2 kilowatts
of just transceivers alone just to drive the
mvlink spine as a result we did it completely
for free over mvlink switch and we were able
to save the 20 kilow for computation this entire
rack is 120 kilowatts so that 20 kilowatts makes
a huge difference it's liquid cooled what
goes in is 25° C about room temperature
what comes out is 45°c about your jacuzzi so room
temperature goes in jacuzzi comes out 2 liters per
second we could we could sell a
peripheral 600,000 Parts somebody used to say
you know you guys make gpus and we do but this
is what a GPU looks like to me when somebody
says GPU I see this two years ago when I saw
a GPU was the hgx it was 70 lb 35,000 Parts our
gpus now are 600,000 parts and 3,000 lb 3,000 lb
3,000 lb that's kind of like the weight of a you
know Carbon Fiber Ferrari I don't know if that's
useful metric but everybody's going I feel it I
feel it I get it I get that now that you mention
that I feel it I don't know what's 3,000 lb okay
so 3,000 lb ton and a half so it's not quite an
elephant so this is what a dgx looks like now
let's see what it looks like in operation okay
let's imagine what is what how do we put this
to work and what does that mean well if you
were to train a GPT model 1.8 trillion parameter
model it took it took about apparently about you
know 3 to 5 months or so uh with 25,000 amp
uh if we were to do it with hopper it would
probably take something like 8,000 gpus and
it would consume 15 megawatts 8,000 gpus on
15 megawatts it would take 90 days about 3 months
and that would allows you to train something that
is you know this groundbreaking AI model and
this is obviously not as expensive as as um
as anybody would think but it's 8,000 8,000
gpus it's still a lot of money and so 8,000
gpus 15 megawatts if you were to use Blackwell
to do this it would only take 2,000 gpus 2,000
gpus same 90 days but this is the amazing part
only 4 me GS of power so from 15 yeah that's
right and that's and that's our goal our goal
is to continuously drive down the cost and the
energy they're directly proportional to each other
cost and energy associated with the Computing so
that we can continue to expand and scale up the
computation that we have to do to train the Next
Generation models well this is training inference
or generation is vitally important going forward
you know probably some half of the time that
Nvidia gpus are in the cloud these days it's
being used for token generation you know they're
either doing co-pilot this or chat you know chat
GPT that or um all these different models that
are being used when you're interacting with it
or generating IM generating images or generating
videos generating proteins generating chemicals
there's a bunch of gener generation going on
all of that is B in the category of computing
we call inference but inference is extremely
hard for large language models because these
large language models have several properties
one they're very large and so it doesn't fit on
one GPU this is Imagine imagine Excel doesn't fit
on one GPU you know and imagine some application
you're running on a daily basis doesn't run
doesn't fit on one computer like a video game
doesn't fit on one computer and most in fact
do and many times in the past in hyperscale
Computing many applic applications for many
people fit on the same computer and now all
of a sudden this one inference application where
you're interacting with this chatbot that chatbot
requires a supercomputer in the back to run it
and that's the future the future is generative
with these chatbots and these chatbots are
trillions of tokens trillions of parameters
and they have to generate tokens at interactive
rates now what does that mean well uh three to
tokens is about a word I you know the the uh
you know space the final frontier these are the
adventures that's like that's like 80 tokens
okay I don't know if that's useful to you and
so you know the art of communications is
is selecting good an good analogies
yeah this is this is not going well
every I don't know what he's talking about
never seen Star Trek and so and so so here
we are we're trying to generate these tokens
when you're interacting with it you're hoping
that the tokens come back to you as quickly as
possible and as quickly as you can read it and
so the ability for Generation tokens is really
important you have to paralyze the work of this
model across many many gpus so that you could
achieve several things one on the one hand you
would like throughput because that throughput
reduces the cost the overall cost per token of
uh generating so your throughput dictates the cost
of of uh delivering the service on the other hand
you have another interactive rate which is another
tokens per second where it's about per user and
that has everything to do with quality of service
and so these two things um uh compete against each
other and we have to find a way to distribute
work across all of these different gpus and
paralyze it in a way that allows us to achieve
both and it turns out the search search space
is enormous you know I told you there's going to
be math involved and everybody's going oh dear I
heard some gasp just now when I put up that slide
you know so so this this right here the the y axis
is tokens per second data center throughput the
x- axis is tokens per second interactivity of the
person and notice the upper right is the best
you want interactivity to be very High number
of tokens per second per user you want the tokens
per second of per data center to be very high the
upper upper right is is terrific however it's very
hard to do that and in order for us to search for
the best answer across every single one of those
intersections XY coordinates okay so you just look
at every single XY coordinate all those blue dots
came from some repartitioning of the software some
optimizing solution has to go and figure out what
whether to use use tensor parallel expert parallel
pipeline parallel or data parallel and distribute
this enormous model across all these G different
gpus and sustain performance that you need this
exploration space would be impossible if not for
the programmability of nvidia's gpus and so we
could because of Cuda because we have such Rich
ecosystem we could explore this universe and find
that green roof line it turns out that green roof
line notice you got tp2 EPA dp4 it means two
parall two uh tensor parallel tensor parallel
across two gpus expert parallels across eight data
parallel across four notice on the other end you
got tensor parallel cross 4 and expert parallel
across 16 the configuration the distribution of
that software it's a different different um
runtime that would produce these different
results and you have to go discover that roof
line well that's just one model and this is just
one configuration of a computer imagine all of the
models being created around the world and all the
different different um uh configurations
of of uh systems that are going to be
available so now that you understand the
basics let's take a look at inference of
Blackwell compared to Hopper and this is this
is the extraordinary thing in one generation
because we created a system that's designed
for trillion parameter gener generative AI the
inference capability of Blackwell is off the
charts and in fact it is some 30 times Hopper
y for large language models for large language
models like Chad GPT and others like it the blue
line is Hopper I gave you imagine we didn't
change the architecture of Hopper we just
made it a bigger chip we just used the latest you
know greatest uh 10 terab you know terabytes per
second we connected the two chips together we got
this giant 208 billion parameter chip how would we
have performed if nothing else changed and it
turns out quite wonderfully quite wonderfully
and that's the purple line but not as great as it
could be and and that's where the fp4 tensor core
the new Transformer engine and very importantly
the MV link switch and the reason for that is
because all these gpus have to share the results
partial products whenever they do all to all all
all gather whenever they communicate with each
other that mvlink switch is communicating almost
10 times faster than what we could do in the
past using the fastest networks Okay so Blackwell
is going to be just an amazing system for a
generative Ai and in the future in the future
data centers are going to be thought of as I
mentioned earlier as an AI Factory an AI Factory's
goal in life is to generate revenues generate
in this case intelligence in this facility not
generating electricity as in AC generator but of
the last Industrial Revolution and this Industrial
Revolution the generation of intelligence and
so this ability is super super important the
excitement of Blackwell is really off the charts
you know when we first when we first um uh you
know this this is a year and a half ago two years
ago I guess two years ago when we first started to
to go to market with hopper you know we had the
benefit of of uh two two uh two csps uh joined
us in a lunch and and we were you know delighted
um and so we had two customers uh we have more
now unbelievable excitement for Blackwell
unbelievable excitement and there's a whole
bunch of different configurations of course I
showed you the configurations that slide into
the hopper form factor so that's easy to upgrade
I showed you examples that are liquid cooled that
are the extreme versions of it one entire rack
that's that's uh connected by mvlink 72 uh we're
going to Blackwell is going to be ramping to the
world's AI companies of which there are so many
now doing amazing work in different modalities the
csps every CSP is geared up all the OEM and odms
Regional clouds Sovereign AIS and Telos all over
the world are signing up to launch with Blackwell
this Blackwell Blackwell would be the the the
most successful product launch in our history
and so I can't wait wait to see that um I want
to thank I want to thank some partners that that
are joining us in this uh AWS is gearing up for
Blackwell they're uh they're going to build the
first uh GPU with secure AI they're uh building
out a 222 exf flops system you know just now
when we animated uh just now the digital twin if
you saw the the all of those clusters are coming
down by the way that is not just art that is a
digital twin of what we're building that's how
big it's going to be besides infrastructure we're
doing a lot of things together with AWS we're Cuda
accelerating stag maker AI we're Cuda accelerating
Bedrock AI uh Amazon robotics is working with us
uh using Nvidia Omniverse and Isaac Sim AWS
Health has Nvidia Health Integrated into it
so AWS has has really leaned into accelerated
Computing uh Google is gearing up for Blackwell
gcp already has A1 100s h100s t4s l4s a whole
Fleet of Nvidia Cuda gpus and they recently
announced the Gemma model that runs across all
of it uh we're work working to optimize uh and
accelerate every aspect of gcp we're accelerating
data proc which for data processing their data
processing engine Jax xlaa vertex Ai and mojoko
for robotics so we're working with uh Google and
gcp across a whole bunch of initiatives uh Oracle
is gearing up for black wellth Oracle is a great
partner of ours for Nvidia dgx cloud and we're
also working together to accelerate something
that's really important to a lot of companies
Oracle database Microsoft is accelerating and
Microsoft is gearing up for Blackwell Microsoft
Nvidia has a wide- ranging partnership we're
accelerating Cuda accelerating all kinds of
services when you when you chat obviously and
uh AI services that are in Microsoft Azure uh
it's very very likely Nvidia is in the back uh
doing the inference and the token generation uh
we built they built the largest Nvidia infiniband
supercomputer basically a digital twin of hours
or a physical twin of hours uh we're bringing the
Nvidia ecosystem to Azure Nvidia djx cloud
to Azure uh Nvidia Omniverse is now hosted
in Azure Nvidia Healthcare is an Azure and all of
it is deeply integrated and deeply connected with
Microsoft fabric the whole industry is gearing up
for Blackwell this is what I'm about to show you
most of the most of the the the uh uh uh scenes
that you've seen so far of Blackwell are the are
the full Fidelity design of Blackwell everything
in our company has a digital twin and in fact this
digital twin idea is it is really spreading and it
it helps it helps companies build very complicated
things perfectly the first time and what could
be more exciting than creating a digital twin to
build a computer that was built in a digital
twin and so let me show you what wistron is
doing to meet the demand for NVIDIA accelerated
Computing widraw one of our leading manufacturing
Partners is building digital twins of Nvidia
dgx and hgx factories using custom software
developed with Omniverse sdks and apis for
their newest Factory wraw started with a
digital twin to virtually integrate their
multi-ad and process simulation data into
a unified view testing and optimizing layouts
in this physically accurate digital environment
increased worker efficency icy by 51% during
construction the Omniverse digital twin was
used to verify that the physical build matched
the digital plans identifying any discrepancies
early has helped avoid costly change orders and
the results have been impressive using a digital
twin helped bring wion's Factory online in half
the time just 2 and 1/2 months instead of five
in operation the Omniverse digital twin helps
widraw rapidly Test new layouts to accommodate
new processes or improve operations in
the existing space and monitor real-time
operations using live iot data from every machine
on the production line which ultimately enabled
wion to reduce End to-end Cycle Times by 50%
and defect rates by 40% with Nvidia Ai and
Omniverse nvidia's Global ecosystem of partners
are building a new era of accelerated AI enabled
[Music] digitalization
[Applause]
that's how we that's the way it's going
to be in the future we're going to
manufacturing everything digitally first
and then we'll manufacture it physically
people ask me how did it start what
got you guys so excited what was it
that you saw that caused you to put it
all in on this incredible idea and it's
this hang on a
second guys that was going to be such a
moment that's what happens when you don't
rehearse this as you know was first
Contact 20 12 alexnet you put a cat
into this computer and it comes out and it says
cat and we said oh my God this is going to change
everything you take 1 million numbers you take
one Million numbers across three channels RGB
these numbers make no sense to anybody you
put it into this software and it compress
it dimensionally reduce it it reduces it from a
million dimensions a million Dimensions it turns
it into three letters one vector one number
and it's generalized you could have the cat
be different cats and and you could have it be the
front of the cat and the back of the cat and you
look at this thing you say unbelievable you mean
any cats yeah any cat and it was able to recognize
all these cats and we realized how it did it
systematically structurally it's scalable how big
can you make it well how big do you want to make
it and so we imagine that this is a completely
new way of writing software and now today as you
know you could have you type in the word c a and
what comes out is a cat it went the other way am
I right unbelievable how is it possible that's
right how is it possible you took three letters
and you generated a million pixels from it and
it made sense well that's the miracle and here we
are just literally 10 years later 10 years later
where we recognize textt we recognize images we
recognize videos and sounds and images not only
do we recognize them we understand their meaning
we understand the meaning of the text that's the
reason why it can chat with you it can summarize
for you it understands the text it understood not
just recognizes the the English it understood the
English it doesn't just recognize the pixels and
understood the pixels and you can you can even
condition it between two modalities you can have
language condition image and generate all kinds
of interesting things well if you can understand
these things what else can you understand
that you've digitized the reason why we
started with text and you know images is because
we digitized those but what else have we digitized
well it turns out we digitized a lot of things
proteins and genes and brain waves anything you
can digitize so long as there's structure we can
probably learn some patterns from it and if we can
learn the patterns from it we can understand its
meaning if we can understand its meaning we might
be able to generate it as well and so therefore
the generative AI Revolution is here well what
else can we generate what else can we learn well
one of the things that we would love to learn we
would love to learn is we would love to learn
climate we would love to learn extreme weather
we would love to learn uh what how we can predict
future weather at Regional scales at sufficiently
high resolution such that we can keep people out
of Harm's Way before harm comes extreme weather
cost the world $150 billion surely more than that
and it's not evenly distributed $150 billion is
concentrated in some parts of the world and of
course to some people of the world we need to
adapt and we need to know what's coming and so
we are creating Earth too a digital twin of the
Earth for predicting weather we and we've made an
extraordinary invention called Civ the ability to
use generative AI to predict weather at extremely
high resolution let's take a look as the earth's
climate changes AI powered weather forecasting
is allowing us to more accurately predict and
track severe storms like super typhoon chanthu
which caused widespread damage in Taiwan and
the surrounding region in 2021 current AI forecast
models can accurately predict the track of storms
but they are limited to 25 km resolution which
can miss important details Invidia cordi is a
revolutionary new generative AI model trained on
high resolution radar assimilated Warf weather
forecasts and air 5 reanalysis data using cordi
extreme events like chanthu can be super resolved
from 25 km to 2 km resolution with 1,000 times
the speed and 3,000 times the Energy Efficiency
of conventional weather models by combining the
speed and accuracy of nvidia's weather forecasting
model forecast net and generative AI models like
cordi we can explore hundreds or even thousands
of kilometer scale Regional weather forecasts
to provide a clear picture of the best worst
and most likely impacts of a storm this wealth
of information can help minimize loss of life
and property damage today cordi is optimized
for Taiwan but soon generative super sampling
will be available as part of the in viia Earth
2 inference service for many regions across the
[Music]
globe the weather company has the trust a source
of global weather predictions we are working
together to accelerate their weather simulation
first principled base of simulation however
they're also going to integrate Earth to cordi so
that they could help businesses and countries do
Regional high resolution weather prediction and
so if you have some weather prediction you'd like
to know like to do uh reach out to the weather
company really exciting really exciting work
Nvidia Healthcare something we started 15 years
ago we're super super excited about this this is
an area where we're very very proud whether
it's Medical Imaging or genene sequencing or
computational chemistry it is very likely that
Nvidia is the computation behind it we've done
so much work in this area today we're announcing
that we're going to do something really really
cool imagine all of these AI models that are being
used to generate images and audio but instead of
images and audio because it understood images
and audio all the digitization that we've done
for genes and proteins and amino acids that
digitalization capability is now now passed
through machine learning so that we understand
the language of Life the ability to understand
the language of Life of course we saw the
first evidence of it with alphafold this
is really quite an extraordinary thing after
Decades of painstaking work the world had only
digitized and reconstructed using cor electron
microscopy or Crystal XR x-ray crystallography
um these different techniques painstaking
reconstructed the protein 200,000 of them
in just what is it less than a year or so
Alpha fold has reconstructed 200 million
proteins basically every protein every of every
living thing that's ever been sequenced this is
completely revolutionary well those models are
incredibly hard to use um for incredibly hard
for people to build and so what we're going to
do is we're going to build them we're going to
build them for uh the the researchers around
the world and it won't be the only one there'll
be many other models that we create and so
let me show you what we're going to do with
it virtual screening for new medicines
is a computationally intractable problem
existing techniques can only scan billions
of compounds and require days on thousands of
standard compute nodes to identify new drug
candidates Nvidia biion Nemo Nims enable a
new generative screening Paradigm using Nims
for protein structure prediction with Alpha
fold molecule generation with MIM and docking
with diff dock we can now generate and Screen
candidate molecules in a matter of minutes MIM
can connect to custom applications to steer the
generative process iteratively optimizing for
desired properties these applications can be
defined with biion Nemo microservices or built
from scratch here a physics based simulation
optimizes for a molecule's ability to bind to
a Target protein while optimizing for other
favorable molecular properties in parallel MIM
generates high quality drug-like molecules that
bind to the Target and are synthesizable
translating to a higher probability of
developing successful medicines faster biion Nemo
is enabling a new paradigm in drug Discovery with
Nims providing OnDemand microservices
that can be combined to build powerful
drug Discovery workflows like denovo protein
design or ided molecule generation for virtual
screening bio Nims are helping researchers
and developers reinvent computational drug
design Nvidia M MIM MIM cord diff there's a whole
bunch of other models whole bunch of other models
computer vision models robotics models and
even of course some really really terrific
open source language models these models are
groundbreaking however it's hard for companies
to use how would you use it how would you bring
it into your company and integrate it into your
workflow how would you package it up and run it
remember earlier I just said that inference is
an extraordinary computation problem how would
you do the optimization for each and every one
of these models and put together the Computing
stack necessary to run that supercomputer so that
you can run the models in your company and so we
have a great idea we're going to invent a new way
invent a new way for you to receive and operate
software this software comes basically in a
digital box we call it a container and we call it
the Nvidia inference micr service a Nim and let me
explain to you what it is a Nim it's a pre-trained
model so it's pretty clever and it is packaged
and optimized to run across nvidia's install
base which is very very large what's inside
it is incredible you have all these pre-trained
state-ofthe-art open source models they could be
open source they could be from one of our partners
it could be created by us like Nvidia mull it is
packaged up with all of its dependencies so Cuda
the right version CNN the right version tensor RT
llm Distributing across the multiple gpus Tred and
inference server all completely packaged together
it's optimized depending on whether you have a
single GPU multi- GPU or multi node of gpus it's
optimized for that and it's connected up with apis
that are simple to use now this think about what
an AI API is an AI API is an interface that you
just talk to and so this is a piece of software in
the future that has a really simple API and that
API called human and these packages incredible
bodies of software will be optimized and packaged
and we'll put it on a website and you can download
it you could take it with you you could run
it in any Cloud you can run it in your own
data center you can run in workstations if it fit
and all you have to do is come to ai. nvidia.com
we call it Nvidia inference microservice but
inside the company we all call it Nims okay
just imagine you know one of some someday there
there's going to be one of these chat Bots and
these chat Bots is going to just be in a Nim and
you you'll uh you'll assemble a whole bunch of
chat Bots and that's the way software is going
to be be built someday how do we build software
in the future it is unlikely that you'll write
it from scratch or write a whole bunch of python
code or anything like that it is very likely that
you assemble a team of AIS there's probably going
to be a super AI that you use that takes the
mission that you give it and breaks it down
into an execution plan some of that execution plan
could be handed off to another Nim that Nim would
maybe uh understand sap the language of sap is
abap it might understand service now and it go
retrieve some information from their platforms
it might then hand that result to another Nim
who that goes off and does some calculation
on it maybe it's an optimization software a
combinatorial optimization algorithm maybe it's
uh you know some just some basic calculator maybe
it's pandas to do some numerical analysis on it
and then it comes back with its answer and it
gets combined with everybody else's and it because
it's been presented with this is what the right
answer should look like it knows what answer what
an what right answers to produce and it presents
it to you we can get a report every single day at
you know top of the hour uh that has something to
do with a bill plan or some forecast or uh some
customer alert or some bugs database or whatever
it happens to be and we could assemble it using
all these Nims and because these Nims have been
packaged up and ready to work on your systems so
long as you have video gpus in your data center in
the cloud this this Nims will work together as a
team and do amazing things and so we decided this
is such a great idea we're going to go do that and
so Nvidia has Nims running all over the company we
have chatbots being created all over the place
and one of the mo most important chatbots of
course is a chip designer chatbot you might not
be surprised we care a lot about building chips
and so we want to build chatbots AI co-pilots that
are co-designers with our engineers and so this
is the way we did it so we got ourselves a llama
llama 2 this is a 70b and it's you know packaged
up in a NM and we asked it you know uh what is a
CTL Well turns out CTL is an internal uh program
and it has a internal proprietary language but
it thought the CTL was a combinatorial timing
logic and so it describes you know conventional
knowledge of CTL but that's not very useful to us
and so we gave it a whole bunch of new examples
you know this is no different than employee
onboarding an employee uh we say you know thanks
for that answer it's completely wrong um and and
uh and then we present to them uh this is what
a CTL is okay and so this is what a CTL is at
Nvidia and the CTL as you can see you know CTL
stands for compute Trace Library which makes
sense you know we were tracing compute Cycles
all the time and it wrote the program isn't that
amazing and so the productivity of our chip
designers can go up this is what you can do with
a Nim first thing you can do with is customize
it we have a service called Nemo microservice
that helps you curate the data preparing the
data so that you could teach this on board
this AI you fine-tune them and then you guardrail
it you can even evaluate the answer evaluate its
performance against um other other examples and
so that's called the Nemo micr service now the
thing that's that's emerging here is this there
are three elements three pillars of what we're
doing the first pillar is of course inventing
the technology for um uh AI models and running
AI models and packaging it up for you the second
is to create tools to help you modify it first
is having the AI technology second is to help you
modify it and third is infrastructure for you to
fine-tune it and if you like deploy it you could
deploy it on our infrastructure called dgx cloud
or you can employ deploy it on Prem you can deploy
it anywhere you like once you develop it it's
yours to take anywhere and so we are effectively
an AI Foundry we will do for you and the industry
on AI what tsmc does for us building chips and
so we go to it with our go to tsmc with our big
Ideas they manufacture and we take it with us and
so exactly the same thing here AI Foundry and the
three pillar ERS are the NIMS Nemo microservice
and dgx Cloud the other thing that you could teach
the Nim to do is to understand your proprietary
information remember inside our company the vast
majority of our data is not in the cloud it's
inside our company it's been sitting there you
know being used all the time and and gosh it's
it's basically invidious intelligence we would
like to take that data learn its meaning like we
learned the meaning of almost anything else that
we just talked about learn its meaning and then
reindex that knowledge into a new type of database
called a vector database and so you essentially
take structured data or unstructured data you
learn its meaning you encode its meaning so now
this becomes an AI database and that AI database
in the future once you create it you can talk to
it and so let me give you an example of what you
could do so suppose you create you get you got a
whole bunch of multi modality data and one good
example of that is PDF so you take the PDF you
take all of your PDFs all the all your favorite
you know the stuff that that is proprietary to
you critical to your company you can encode it
just as we encoded pixels of a cat and it becomes
the word cat we can encode all of your PDF and it
turns into vectors that are now stored inside
your vector database it becomes the proprietary
information of your company and once you have
that proprietary information you can chat to
it it's an it's a smart database and so you just
ch chat with data and how how much more enjoyable
is that you know we for for our software team
you know they just chat with the bugs database
you know how many bugs was there last night um
are we making any progress and then after you're
done talking to this uh bugs database you need
therapy and so so we have another chatbot for
you you can do
it okay so we call this Nemo Retriever and the
reason for that is because ultimately it's job
is to go retrieve information as quickly as
possible and you just talk to it hey retrieve
me this information it goes if brings it back to
you and do you mean this you go yeah perfect okay
and so we call it the Nemo retriever well the
Nemo service helps you create all these things
and we have all all these different Nims we
even have Nims of digital humans I'm Rachel
your AI care manager okay so so it's a really
short clip but there were so many videos to
show you I guess so many other demos to show
you and so I I had to cut this one short but
this is Diana she is a digital human Nim
and and uh you just talked to her and she's
connected in this case to Hippocratic ai's large
language model for healthcare and it's truly
amazing she is just super smart about Healthcare
things you know and so after you're done after my
my Dwight my VP of software engineering talks to
the chatbot for bugs database then you come over
here and talk to Diane and and so so uh Diane
is is um completely animated with AI and she's
a digital human uh there's so many companies that
would like to build they're sitting on gold mines
the the Enterprise IT industry is sitting on a
gold mine it's a gold mine because they have so
much understanding of of uh the way work is
done they have all these amazing tools that
have been created over the years and they're
sitting on a lot of data if they could take
that gold mine and turn them into co-pilots
these co-pilots could help us do things and
so just about every it franchise it platform in
the world that has valuable tools that people use
is sitting on a gold mine for co-pilots and
they would like to build their own co-pilots
and their own chatbots and so we're announcing
that Nvidia AI foundary is working with some
of the world's great companies sap generates
87% of the world's Global Commerce basically
the world runs on sap we run on sap Nvidia and
sap are building sap Jewel co-pilots uh using
Nvidia Nemo and dgx cloud service now they run
80 85% of the world's Fortune 500 companies run
their people and customer service operations on
service now and they're using Nvidia AI Foundry
to build service now uh assist virtual assistance
cohesity backs up the world's data they're sitting
on a gold mine of data hundreds of exobytes of
data over 10,000 companies Nvidia AI Foundry is
working with them helping them build their Gaia
generative AI agent snowflake is a company that
stores the world's uh digital Warehouse in
the cloud and serves over 3 billion queries
a day for 10,000 Enterprise customers snowflake is
working with Nvidia AI Foundry to build co-pilots
with Nvidia Nemo and Nims net apppp nearly half
of the files in the world are stored on Prem on
net apppp Nvidia AI Foundry is helping them uh
build chat Bots and co-pilots like those Vector
databases and retrievers with Nvidia neemo and
Nims and we have a great partnership with Dell
everybody who everybody who is building these
chat Bots and generative AI when you're ready
to run it you're going to need an AI Factory and
nobody is better at Building end-to-end Systems
of very large scale for the Enterprise than
Dell and so anybody any company every company
will need to build AI factories and it turns out
that Michael is here he's happy to take your order
ladies and gentlemen Michael
del okay let's talk about the next wave of
Robotics the next wave of AI robotics physical
AI so far all of the AI that we've talked about is
one computer data comes into one computer lots of
the world's if you will experience in digital
text form the AI imitates Us by reading a lot
of the language to predict the next words it's
imitating You by studying all of the patterns
and all the other previous examples of course it
has to understand context and so on so forth but
once it understands the context it's essentially
imitating you we take all of the data we put it
into a system like dgx we compress it into a
large language model trillions and trillions of
parameters become billions and billion trillions
of tokens becomes billions of parameters these
billions of parameters becomes your AI well
in order for us to go to the next wave of AI
where the AI understands the physical world we're
going to need three computers the first computer
is still the same computer it's that AI computer
that now is going to be watching video and maybe
it's doing synthetic data generation and maybe
there's a lot of human examples just as we have
human examples in text form we're going to have
human examples in articulation form and the AIS
will watch us understand what is happening and try
to adapt it for themselves into the context and
because it can generalize with these Foundation
models maybe these robots can also perform in
the physical world fairly generally so I just
described in very simple terms essentially what
just happened in large language models except
the chat GPT moment for robotics may be right
around the corner and so we've been building
the end to-end systems for robotics for some
time I'm super super proud of the work we have
the AI system dgx we have the lower system which
is called agx for autonomous systems the world's
first robotics processor when we first built this
thing people are what are you guys building
it's a s so it's one chip it's designed to be
very low power but it's designed for high-speed
sensor processing and Ai and so if you want to
run Transformers in a car or you want to run
Transformers in a in a you know anything um
that moves uh we have the perfect computer for you
it's called the Jetson and so the dgx on top for
training the AI the Jetson is the autonomous
processor and in the middle we need another
computer whereas large language models have the
benefit of you providing your examples and then
doing reinforcement learning human feedback what
is the reinforcement learning human feedback of a
robot well it's reinforcement learning physical
feedback that's how you align the robot that's
how you that's how the robot knows that as
it's learning these articulation capabilities
and manipulation capabilities it's going to adapt
properly into the laws of physics and so we need
a simulation engine that represents the world
digitally for the robot so that the robot has
a gym to go learn how to be a robot we call that
virtual world Omniverse and the computer that runs
Omniverse is called ovx and ovx the computer
itself is hosted in the Azure Cloud okay and
so basically we built these three things these
three systems on top of it we have algorithms
for every single one now I'm going to show you one
super example of how Ai and Omniverse are going to
work together the example I'm going to show you
is kind of insane but it's going to be very very
close to tomorrow it's a robotics building this
robotics building is called a warehouse inside the
robotics building are going to be some autonomous
systems some of the autonomous systems are going
to be called humans and some of the autonomous
systems are going to be called forklifts and
these autonomous systems are going to interact
with each other of course autonomously and it's
going to be overlooked upon by this Warehouse to
keep everybody out of Harm's Way the warehouse
is essentially an air traffic controller and
whenever it sees something happening it will
redirect traffic traffic and give New Way points
just new way points to the robots and the people
and they'll know exactly what to do this warehouse
this building you can also talk to of course you
could talk to it hey you know sap Center how are
you feeling today for example and so you could
ask the same the warehouse the same questions
basically the system I just described will have
Omniverse Cloud that's hosting the virtual
simulation and AI running on djx cloud and
all of this is running in real time let's take
a look the future of heavy industri starts as a
digital twin the AI agents helping robots workers
and infrastructure navigate unpredictable events
in complex industrial spaces will be built
and evaluated first in sophisticated digital
twins this Omniverse digital twin of a 100,000 ft
Warehouse is operating as a simulation environment
that integrates digital workers amrs running the
Nvidia Isaac receptor stack centralized activity
maps of the entire Warehouse from 100 simulated
ceiling mount cameras using Nvidia metropolis
and AMR route planning with Nvidia Koop software
in Loop testing of AI agents in this physically
accurate simulated environment enables us to
evaluate and refine how the system adapts to real
world unpredictability here an incident occurs
along this amr's planned route blocking its path
as it moves to pick up a pallet Nvidia Metropolis
updates and sends a realtime occupancy map to kopt
where a new optimal route is calculated the AMR
is enabled to see around corners and improve its
Mission efficiency with generative AI powered
Metropolis Vision Foundation models operators
can even ask questions using natural language the
visual model understands nuanced activity and can
offer immediate insights to improve operations
all of the sensor data is created in simulation
and passed to the real-time AI running as Nvidia
inference microservices or Nims and when the AI is
ready to be deployed in the physical twin the real
Warehouse we connect metropolis and Isaac Nims
to real sensors with the ability for continuous
Improvement of both the digital twin and the AI
models isn't that incredible and so remember
remember a future facility Warehouse Factory
building will be software defined and so the
software is running how else would you test
the software so you you you test the software to
building the warehouse the optimization system in
the digital twin what about all the robots all of
those robots you are seeing just now they're all
running their own autonomous robotic stack and so
the way you integrate software in the future cicd
in the future for robotic systems is with digital
twins we've made Omniverse a lot easier to access
we're going to create basically Omniverse Cloud
apis four simple API and a channel and you can
connect your application to it so this is this
is going to be as wonderfully beautifully simple
in the future that Omniverse is going to be and
with these apis you're going to have these magical
digital twin capability we also have turned om ver
into an AI and integrated it with the ability to
chat USD the the language of our language is
you know human and Omniverse is language as
it turns out is universal scene description and
so that language is rather complex and so we've
taught our Omniverse uh that language and so
you can speak to it in English and it would
directly generate USD and it would talk back
in USD but Converse back to you in English you
could also look for information in this world
semantically instead of the world being encoded
semantically in in language now it's encoded
semantically in scenes and so you could ask
it of of uh certain objects or certain conditions
and certain scenarios and it can go and find that
scenario for you it also can collaborate with
you in generation you could design some things
in 3D it could simulate some things in 3D or
you could use AI to generate something in 3D
let's take a look at how this is all going to work
we have a great partnership with Seamans Seamans
is the world's largest industrial engineering
and operations platform you've seen now so many
different companies in the industrial space heavy
Industries is one of the greatest final frontiers
of it and we finally now have the Necessary
Technology to go and make a real impact seens
is building the industrial metaverse and today
we're announcing that Seamans is connecting their
Crown Jewel accelerator to Nvidia Omniverse let's
take a look seens technology is transformed every
day for everyone team Center acts our leading
product life cycle management software from the
sems accelerator platform is used every day by
our customers to develop and deliver products
at scale now we are bringing the real and the
digital worlds even Closer by integrating Nvidia
Ai and Omniverse Technologies into team Center X
Omniverse apis enable data interoperability and
physics-based rendering to Industrial scale design
and Manufacturing projects our customers HD market
leader in sustainable ship manufacturing builds
ammonia and hydrogen power chips often comprising
over 7 million discrete Parts with Omniverse apis
team Center X lets companies like HD yundai unify
and visualize these massive engineering data
sets interactively and integrate generative AI
to generate 3D objects or HDR I backgrounds
to see their projects in context the result
an ultra inuitive photoal physics-based digital
twin that eliminates waste and errors delivering
huge savings in cost and time and we are building
this for collaboration whether across more semens
accelerator tools like seens anex or Star CCM
Plus or across teams working on their favorite
devices in the same scene together in this is
just the beginning working with Nvidia we will
bring accelerated Computing generative Ai and
Omniverse integration across the Sean accelerator
portfolio the pro the the professional
the professional voice actor happens to
be a good friend of mine Roland Bush
who happens to be the CEO of seens
once you get Omniverse connected into your
workflow your ecosystem from the beginning
of your design to engineering to manufacturing
planning all the way to digital twin operations
once you connect everything together it's insane
how much productivity you can get and it's just
really really wonderful all of a sudden everybody
is operating on the same ground truth you don't
have to exchange data and convert data make
mistakes everybody is working on the same
ground truth from the design Department to the
art Department the architecture Department all
the way to the engineering and even the marketing
department let's take a look at how Nissan has
integrated Omniverse into their workflow
and it's all because it's connected by all
these wonderful tools and these developers
that we're working with take a look unbel
[Music]
for
that was not an animation that was Omniverse today
we're announcing that Omniverse
Cloud streams to The Vision Pro
and it is very very strange that you walk around
virtual doors when I was getting out of that car
and everybody does it it is really really quite
amazing Vision Pro connected to Omniverse portals
you into Omniverse and because all of these CAD
tools and all these different design tools are
now integrated and connected to Omniverse you can
have this type of workflow really incredible let's
talk about robotics everything that moves will be
robotic there's no question about that it's safer
it's more convenient and one of the largest
Industries is going to be Automotive we build
the robotic stack from top to bottom as I was
mentioned from the computer system but in the case
of self-driving cars including the self-driving
application at the end of this year or I guess
beginning of next year we will be shipping in
Mercedes and then shortly after that jlr and
so these autonomous robotic systems are software
defined they take a lot of work to do has computer
vision has obviously artificial intelligence
control and planning all kinds of very complicated
technology and takes years to refine we're
building the entire stack however we open up our
entire stack for all of the automotive industry
this is just the way we work the way we work in
every single industry we try to build as much of
it as we can so that we understand it but then
we open it up so everybody can access it whether
you would like to buy just our computer which is
the world's only full functional save asld system
that can run AI this functional safe asld quality
computer or the operating system on top or of
course our data centers which is in basically
every AV company in the world however you would
like to enjoy it we're delighted by it today we're
announcing that byd the world's largest ev company
is adopting our next Generation it's called Thor
Thor is designed for Transformer engines Thor
our next Generation AV computer will be used by
byd you probably don't know this fact that we
have over a million robotics developers we created
Jetson this robotics computer we're so proud of
it the amount of software that goes on top of it
is insane but the reason why we can do it at all
is because it's 100% Cuda compatible everything
that we do everything that we do in our company
is in service of our developers and by us being
able to maintain this Rich ecosystem and make
it compatible with everything that you access
from us we can bring all of that incredible
capability to this little tiny computer we
call Jetson a robotics computer we also today
are announcing this incredibly Advanced new SDK
we call it Isaac perceptor Isaac perceptor most
most of the Bots today are pre-programmed they're
either following rails on the ground digital rails
or theyd be following April tags but in the future
they're going to have perception and the reason
why you want that is so that you could easily
program it you say would you like to go from
point A to point B and it will figure out a way
to navigate its way there so by only programming
waypoints the entire route could be adaptive the
entire environment could be reprogrammed just
as I showed you at the very beginning with the
warehouse you can't do that with pre-programmed
agvs if those boxes fall down they just all gum
up and they just wait there for somebody to come
clear it and so now with the Isaac perceptor
we have incredible state-of-the-art Vision
odometry 3D reconstruction and in addition
to 3D reconstruction depth perception the reason
for that is so that you can have two modalities
to keep an eye on what's happening in the world
Isaac perceptor the most used robot today is the
manipulator manufacturing arms and they are also
pre-programmed the computer vision algorithms the
AI algorithms the control and path planning
algorithms that are geometry aware incredibly
computational intensive we have made these Cuda
accelerated so we have the world's first Cuda
accelerated motion planner that is geometry aware
you put something in front of it it comes up with
a new plan and our articulates around it it has
excellent perception for pose estimation of a 3D
object not just not it's pose in 2D but it's pose
in 3D so it has to imagine what's around and how
best to grab it so the foundation pose the grip
foundation and the um articulation algorithms
are now available we call it Isaac manipulator and
they also uh just run on nvidia's computers we are
are starting to do some really great work in the
next generation of Robotics the next generation
of Robotics will likely be a humanoid robotics
we now have the Necessary Technology and as I
was describing earlier the Necessary Technology
to imagine generalized human robotics in a way
human robotics is likely easier and the reason
for that is because we have a lot more imitation
training data that we can provide there robots
because we are constructed in a very similar
way it is very likely that the human robotics
will be much more useful in our world because
we created the world to be something that we can
interoperate in and work well in and the way that
we set up our workstations and Manufacturing
and Logistics they were designed for for humans
they were designed for people and so these human
robotics will likely be much more productive to
deploy while we're creating just like we're doing
with the others the entire stack starting from the
top a foundation model that learns from watching
video human IM human examples it could be in video
form it could be in virtual reality form we then
created a gym for it called Isaac reinforcement
learning gym which allows the humanoid robot to
learn how to adapt to the physical world and then
an incredible computer the same computer that's
going to go into a robotic car this computer
will run inside a human or robot called Thor
it's designed for Transformer engines we've
combined several of these into one video this is
something that you're going to really love take a
look it's not enough for humans
to [Music] imagine we have to
invent and explore real and push
Beyond what's been done fair amount of
detail we create smarter and
faster we push it to fail so it can
learn we teach it then help it teach
itself we broaden its understanding
to take on new
challenges with absolute
precision and succeed we make it perceive and
move and even
reason so it can share our world with us
[Music]
1:52:22.520,1193:02:47.295
this is where inspiration leads us the
next Frontier this is Nvidia Project
Groot a general purpose Foundation model for
humanoid robot learning the group model takes
multimodal instructions and past interactions
as input and produces the next action for the
robot to execute we developed Isaac lab a
robot learning application to train gr on
Omniverse Isaac Sim and we scale out with osmo a
new compute orchestration service that coordinates
work flows across dgx systems for training and
ovx systems for simulation with these tools we
can train Groot in physically based simulation
and transfer zero shot to the real world the
Groot model will enable a robot to learn from a
handful of human demonstrations so it can help
with everyday tasks and emulate human movement
just by observing us this is made possible
with nvidia's technologies that can understand
humans from videos train models and simulation
and ultimately deploy them directly to physical
robots connecting group to a large language model
even allows it to generate motions by following
natural language instructions hi go1 can you give
me a high five sure thing let's high five can
you give us some cool moves sure check this out
all this incredible intelligence is
powered by the new Jetson Thor robotics
chips designed for Groot built for the
future with Isaac lab osmo and Groot
we're providing the building blocks
for the next generation of AI powered
[Applause]
robotics [Music]
about the same
size the soul of Nvidia the intersection
of computer Graphics physics artificial
intelligence it all came to bear at this moment
the name of that project general robotics
003 I know super good super good well
I think we have some special guests do
[Music] we hey
guys so I understand you guys
are powered by Jetson they're
powered by Jetson little Jetson robotics
computers inside they learn to walk in Isaac
Sim ladies and gentlemen this this is orange and
this is the famous green they are the
bdx robots of Disney amazing Disney
research come on you guys let's wrap
up let's go five things where you
going I sit right
here Don't Be Afraid come here green hurry
up what are you saying no it's
not time to eat it's not time
to I'll I'll give you a snack in a moment let
me finish up real quick come on green hurry up
stop wasting time five things five things first
a new Industrial Revolution every data center
should be accelerated a trillion dollars worth
of installed data centers will become modernized
over the next several years second because
of the computational capability we brought
to bear a new way of doing software has emerged
generative AI which is going to create new in new
infrastructure dedicated to doing one thing and
one thing only not for multi-user data centers but
AI generators these AI generation will create
incredibly valuable software a new Industrial
Revolution second the computer of this revolution
the computer of this generation generative AI
trillion parameters blackw insane amounts of
computers and computing third I'm trying to
concentrate good job third new computer new
computer creates new types of software new
type of software should be distributed in a
new way so that it can on the one hand be an
endpoint in the cloud and easy to use but still
allow you to take it with you because it is your
intelligence your intelligence should be pack
packaged up in a way that allows you to take
it with you we call them Nims and third
these Nims are going to help you create a
new type of application for the future not
one that you wrote completely from scratch
but you're going to integrate them like teams
create these applications we have a fantastic
capability between Nims the AI technology the
tools Nemo and the infrastructure dgx cloud in
our AI Foundry to help you create proprietary
applications proprietary chat Bots and then
lastly everything that moves in the future
will be robotic you're not going to be the
only one and these robotic systems whether they
are humanoid amrs self-driving cars forklifts
manipulating arms they will all need one thing
Giant stadiums warehouses factories there can to
be factories that are robotic orchestrating
factories uh manufacturing lines that are
robotics building cars that are robotics these
systems all need one thing they need a platform
a digital platform a digital twin platform and
we call that Omniverse the operating system of
the robotics World these are the five things that
we talked about today what does Nvidia look like
what does Nvidia look like when we talk about
gpus there's a very different image that I have
when I when people ask me about gpus first I see
a bunch of software stacks and things like that
and second I see this this is what we announce
to you today this is Blackwell this is the plat
amazing amazing processors MV link switches
networking systems and the system design is
a miracle this is Blackwell and this
to me is what a GPU looks like in my
mind listen orange green I think we
have one more treat for everybody
what do you think should we okay we
have one more thing to show you roll
[Music]
it
he
[Music]
2:01:21.920,1193:02:47.295
[Music] m
[Music] yeah [Music]
[Music]
thank you thank you have a great have a
great GTC thank you all for coming thank
you